<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Root xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<Row>
		<NAME>Give Praising Speech</NAME>
		<ID>A1</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>This Action will see you give a magnaminous speech in honor of this character. Based somewhat on your Charisma, it will always have a positive effect on the character you are feting, as well as on the characters who also have a positive relationship with that character.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>Issue Public Reprimand</NAME>
		<ID>A2</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL CREATE A PUBLIC REPRIMAND TO THE CHARACTER THAT IS HEARD THROUGHOUT THEIR SPHERE OF INFLUENCE. OBVIOUSLY, THE CHARACTER REPRIMANDED WON'T LIKE IT, NOR WILL THEIR HOUSE, BUT THEIR ENEMIES AND RIVALS CERTAINLY WILL…</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>CHALLENGE/INSULT</NAME>
		<ID>A3</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL PUBLICALLY CHALLENGE ANOTHER CHARACTER. IT WILL GENERATE A CHALLENGE THAT LASTS FOR 10 TURNS. IF THE CHALLENGED CHARACTER DECLINES TO RESPOND, THEY LOSE INFLUENCE. IF THEY ACCEPT, A CHALLENGE IS GENERATED, WITH THE WINNER GAINING INFLUENCE, AND THE LOSER LOSING DOUBLE THAT AMOUNT.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>EXPRESS SUPPORT</NAME>
		<ID>A4</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL EXPRESS SUPPORT PUBLICALLY FOR ANOTHER CHARACTER. ADDS A SMALL AMOUNT OF INFLUENCE TO THE SUPPORTED CHARACTER DEPENDING ON THE SUPPORTING CHARCTER'S INFLUENCE. WILL ANGER THOSE WHO HAVE A NEGATIVE RELATIONSHIP WITH THE SUPPORTED CHARACTER.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>GIVE SIGNIFICANT GIFT</NAME>
		<ID>A5</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL GIVE A SIGNIFICANT GIFT TO ANOTHER CHARACTER, IN LINE WITH THEIR POSITION AND INFLUENCE. GREAT FOR WHEN YOU NEED TO REPAIR RELATIONSHIPS QUICKLY, BUT OTHERS CAN BECOME JEALOUS. ALSO, REPEATED GIFTS HAVE LESS EFFECT.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
<Row>
		<NAME>ORDER TO CHANGE EXPORT</NAME>
		<ID>A6</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION ASKS A CHARACTER TO CHANGE THEIR EXPORT TO SOMETHING THAT MAY BE MORE PROFITABLE OR SOMETHING THAT IS NEEDED FOR THE HOUSE CONTROLLING THE PLANET.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>FALSE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>FALSE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>FALSE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
  <Row>
    <NAME>GIVE INSULTING SPEECH</NAME>
		<ID>A7</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>This Action sees you give a highly inflammatory speech against a certain character. It's public and it's guaranteed to piss them off, as well as their House if they're high enough on the chain.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>0</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>TRUE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>TRUE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
  </Row>
  <Row>
    <NAME>Make A Peace Offering</NAME>
		<ID>A8</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>If these characters are feuding or at war, this Action attempts to make amends with a gift of some sort. These gifts are usually significant and come out of the character's personal funds. The gift may not always be accepted, however...</DESCRIPTION>
    <RELSTATES>11,13,9,7,19,20,5</RELSTATES>
		<CATEGORY>3</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>TRUE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>TRUE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
  </Row>
</Root>