<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Root xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<Row>
		<NAME>GIVE PRAISING SPEECH</NAME>
		<ID>A1</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL HAVE YOU GIVE A SPEECH TO THE PLANET/SYSTEM/PROVINCE THAT IS THE CHARACTER'S AOI, PRAISING THEIR WORK FOR THE EMPIRE. SHOULD INCREASE THE CHARACTER'S POSUP AND YOUR RELATIONS. MAY BACKFIRE IF YOU HAVE LOW POWER OR A LOW CHARISMA RATING.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>POLITICAL</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>ISSUE PUBLIC REPRIMAND</NAME>
		<ID>A2</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL CREATE A PUBLIC REPRIMAND TO THE CHARACTER THAT IS HEARD THROUGHOUT THEIR SPHERE OF INFLUENCE. OBVIOUSLY, THE CHARACTER REPRIMANDED WON'T LIKE IT, NOR WILL THEIR HOUSE, BUT THEIR ENEMIES AND RIVALS CERTAINLY WILL…</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>POLITICAL</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>CHALLENGE/INSULT</NAME>
		<ID>A3</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL PUBLICALLY CHALLENGE ANOTHER CHARACTER. IT WILL GENERATE A CHALLENGE THAT LASTS FOR 10 TURNS. IF THE CHALLENGED CHARACTER DECLINES TO RESPOND, THEY LOSE INFLUENCE. IF THEY ACCEPT, A CHALLENGE IS GENERATED, WITH THE WINNER GAINING INFLUENCE, AND THE LOSER LOSING DOUBLE THAT AMOUNT.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>POLITICAL</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>EXPRESS SUPPORT</NAME>
		<ID>A4</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL EXPRESS SUPPORT PUBLICALLY FOR ANOTHER CHARACTER. ADDS A SMALL AMOUNT OF INFLUENCE TO THE SUPPORTED CHARACTER DEPENDING ON THE SUPPORTING CHARCTER'S INFLUENCE. WILL ANGER THOSE WHO HAVE A NEGATIVE RELATIONSHIP WITH THE SUPPORTED CHARACTER.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>POLITICAL</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
	<Row>
		<NAME>GIVE SIGNIFICANT GIFT</NAME>
		<ID>A5</ID>
		<DESCRIPTION>THIS ACTION WILL GIVE A SIGNIFICANT GIFT TO ANOTHER CHARACTER, IN LINE WITH THEIR POSITION AND INFLUENCE. GREAT FOR WHEN YOU NEED TO REPAIR RELATIONSHIPS QUICKLY, BUT OTHERS CAN BECOME JEALOUS. ALSO, REPEATED GIFTS HAVE LESS EFFECT.</DESCRIPTION>
		<CATEGORY>POLITICAL</CATEGORY>
		<VIC_E>TRUE</VIC_E>
		<SYSGOV_E>TRUE</SYSGOV_E>
		<PROGOV_E>TRUE</PROGOV_E>
		<PRIME_E>TRUE</PRIME_E>
		<ALL_E>FALSE</ALL_E>
		<INQ_E>FALSE</INQ_E>
		<EMP_NEAR>FALSE</EMP_NEAR>
		<EMP_ACTION>TRUE</EMP_ACTION>
	</Row>
</Root>